Guide to the Dramatic Museum Realia,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series I: Puppets
  - Subseries I.9: Japan
    - P56 Accession
      - Banner on stand with Japanese characters, P56.12 (Box 47)
      - Banner on stand with Japanese characters, P56.13 (Box 47)
    - P95 Accession
      - Japanese male doll, P95 (Box 22)
  - Subseries I.10: Mexico
    - P48 Accession
      - Jigging puppet of black figure with white hat, P48.01 (Box 40)
      - Jigging puppet of male in blue and white cap, P48.02 (Box 40)
      - Jigging puppet of woman with polka dot skirt, P48.03 (Box 40)
      - Jigging puppet of female in polka dot top and purple skirt, P48.04 (Box 40)
      - Jigging puppet of female in purple dress, P48.05 (Box 40)
      - Jigging puppet of male in white shirt and pants with pink belt, P48.06 (Box 40)
      - Jigging puppet of pink [devil], P48.07 (Box 40)
      - Jigging puppet of man with mustache and white hat, P48.08 (Box 40)
      - Jigging puppet of man with mustache and white hat, P48.10 (Box 40)
      - Jigging puppet of clown in white with black polka dots, P48.11 (Box 40)
  - Subseries I.11: Russia
    - P89 Accession
      - Beggar doll made by Russian emigres living in Iran during WWII., P89.01 (Box 34)
      - Beggar doll made by Russian emigres living in Iran during WWII., P89.02 (Box 34)
      - Beggar doll made by Russian emigres living in Iran during WWII., P89.03 (Box 34)
  - Subseries I.12: Thailand
    - P54 Accession
      - Lakshana shadow puppet, P54.01 (Box 31)
      - Laba shadow puppet, P54.02 (Box 30)
      - Sita shadow puppet, P54.03 (Box 30)
    - P55 Accession
      - Head with headdress for court dancer figurine, P55.01 (Box 47)
      - Head with headdress for court dancer figurine, P55.02 (Box 47)
      - Head with headdress for court dancer figurine, P55.03 (Box 47)
      - Head with headdress for court dancer figurine, P55.04 (Box 47)
      - Head with headdress for court dancer figurine, P55.05 (Box 47)
      - Head with headdress for court dancer figurine, P55.06 (Box 47)
      - Head with headdress for court dancer figurine, P55.07 (Box 47)
      - Head with headdress for court dancer figurine, P55.08 (Box 47)
      - Head with headdress for court dancer figurine, P55.09 (Box 47)
      - Head with headdress for court dancer figurine, P55.10 (Box 47)
      - Head with headdress for court dancer figurine, P55.11 (Box 47)
      - Head with headdress for court dancer figurine, P55.12 (Box 47)
    - P72 Accession
      - Sculpture of Siamese dancer, P72.01 (Box 47)
      - Sculpture of Siamese dancer, P72.02 (Box 47)
    - TSP Accession
      - Thai shadow puppet, TSP01 (Box TSP01)
      - Thai shadow puppet, TSP02 (Box TSP02)
      - Thai shadow puppet, TSP03 (Box TSP03)
      - Thai shadow puppet, TSP04 (Box TSP04)
      - Thai shadow puppet, TSP05 (Box TSP05)
      - Thai shadow puppet, TSP06 (Box TSP06)
      - Thai shadow puppet, TSP07 (Box TSP07)
      - Thai shadow puppet, TSP08 (Box TSP08)
      - Thai shadow puppet, TSP09 (Box TSP09)
      - Thai shadow puppet, TSP10 (Box TSP10)
      - Thai shadow puppet, TSP11 (Box TSP11)
      - Thai shadow puppet, TSP12 (Box TSP12)
      - Thai shadow puppet, TSP13 (Box TSP13)
      - Thai shadow puppet, TSP14 (Box TSP14)
      - Thai shadow puppet, TSP15 (Box TSP15)
      - Thai shadow puppet, TSP16 (Box TSP16)
      - Thai shadow puppet, TSP17 (Box TSP17)
      - Thai shadow puppet, TSP18 (Box TSP18)
      - Thai shadow puppet, TSP19 (Box TSP19)
      - Thai shadow puppet, TSP20 (Box TSP20)
      - Thai shadow puppet, TSP21 (Box TSP21)
      - Thai shadow puppet, TSP22 (Box TSP22)
      - Thai shadow puppet, TSP23 (Box TSP23)
      - Thai shadow puppet, TSP24 (Box TSP24)
  - Subseries I.13: Turkey
    - P13 Accession
      - Turkish shadow puppet of building with columns, 1800-1899; P13.01 (Box 23)
      - Turkish shadow puppet of rhinoceros, 1800-1899; P13.02 (Box 23)
      - Turkish shadow puppet of man with goat body, 1800-1899; P13.03 (Box 23)
      - Turkish shadow puppet of man with goat body, 1800-1899; P13.04 (Box 23)
      - Turkish shadow puppet of man with red striped cap, 1800-1899; P13.05 (Box 23)
      - Turkish shadow puppet of trees, 1800-1899; P13.06 (Box 23)
      - Turkish shadow puppet of man with horse/donkey body, 1800-1899; P13.07 (Box 23)
      - Turkish shadow puppet of Devil holding watering can, 1800-1899; P13.08 (Box 23)
      - Turkish shadow puppet of trees, 1800-1899; P13.09 (Box 23)
      - Turkish shadow puppet of rocks, 1800-1899; P13.10 (Box 23)
      - Turkish shadow puppet of woman holding flower, 1800-1899; P13.11 (Box 23)
      - Turkish shadow puppet of trees, 1800-1899; P13.12 (Box 23)
      - Turkish shadow puppet of tree, 1800-1899; P13.13 (Box 23)
      - Turkish shadow puppet of flag with X marked on it, 1800-1899; P13.14 (Box 23)
      - Turkish shadow puppet of small square, 1800-1899; P13.15 (Box 23)
      - Turkish shadow puppet of chest of drawers, 1800-1899; P13.17 (Box 23)
      - Turkish shadow puppet of closet, 1800-1899; P13.18 (Box 23)
      - Turkish shadow puppet of trees, 1800-1899; P13.19 (Box 23)
      - Turkish shadow puppet of L-shaped piece and attachment, 1800-1899; P13.20 (Box 23)
      - Turkish shadow puppet of monkey on man's back, holding gun, 1800-1899; P13.21 (Box 23)
  - Subseries I.14: United States
    - P22 Accession
      - Little Boy Blue marionette, P22.01 (Box 6)
    - P30 Accession
      - Weight-lifter pantin, P30.01 (Box 24)
      - Toe dancer pantin, P30.02 (Box 24)
      - Wire walker pantin, P30.03 (Box 24)
      - Trapeze artist pantin, P30.04 (Box 24)
      - Horizontal bar gymnast pantin, P30.05 (Box 24)
      - Loop-the-loop bicyclist pantin, P30.06 (Box 24)
      - Elephant and trainer pantin, P30.07 (Box 24)
      - Clown musician and dog pantin, P30.08 (Box 24)
      - Clown with two dogs on see-saw pantin, P30.09 (Box 24)
      - Horse with trainer pantin, P30.10 (Box 24)
    - P47 Accession
      - Oedipus (sighted) marionette, 1931; P47.01; Robert Edmond Jones; Remo Bufano (Box 57)
      - Jocasta marionette, 1931; P47.02; Robert Edmond Jones; Remo Bufano (Box 58)
      - Don Quixote marionette, 1924; P47.03; Remo Bufano (Box 59)
      - Giant marionette, 1894-1948; P47.04; Remo Bufano (Box 49)
      - Dragon marionette, 1923; P47.05; Remo Bufano (Box 48)
      - Model for Clown puppet, 1934-1935; P47.06; Remo Bufano (Box 56)
  - Subseries I.15: Puppets of Unknown Origin
    - P70s Accession
      - Dollhouse accessories, P73 (Box 51)
        - Model of Shakespeare's house, apparently for tealights, P74 (Box 41)
      - P.75 Accession
        - Ceramic figurine of unnamed comedian, with green jacketand red waistcoat, P75.01 (Box 41)
        - Fred French ceramic figurine, P75.02 (Box 41)
        - JH Stead ceramic figurine, P75.03 (Box 41)
      - P.76 Accession
        - Small Textile, P76.01 (Box 44)
        - Small Textile, P76.02 (Box 44)
        - Small Textile, P76.03 (Box 33)
      - P.77 Accession
        - Eskimo hand puppet with fur trim, P77.01 (Box 2)
        - Hand puppet of female with head scarf, P77.02 (Box 2)
      - P.78 Accession
        - Shadow puppet, P78.01 (Box 60)
        - Shadow puppet, P78.02 (Box 61)
      - P.79 Accession
        - Model of Helen Hayes as Queen Victoria, P79; Luis Hidalgo (Box 54)
    - P80s Accession
      - Wayang kerutjil puppet, P80 (Box 30)
      - Weapon fragment belonging to an unidentified puppet, P83 (Box 15)
      - Apron for a puppet, P87 (Box 32)
        - Shadow puppet, P88 (Box 29)
    - P.90s Accession
      - Wooden figurine of Shahuntola and Deer, P90 (Box 22)
      - Figurine of elongated man, P93 (Box 46)
      - Japanese theater diorama, P94 (Box 52)
- Series II: Masks
  This collection now contains 128 masks, mask molds, wigs, and plaster mask reproductions. The oldest mask in the collection is an 18th century Javanese dance mask. A gift from Prof. and Mrs. Samuel Eilenberg in 1963, the mask is also the most recent acquisition. The newest masks in the collection were made in 1955 for an American production of Lysistrata. The collection includes items from Japan, Italy, Java, Sri Lanka, Thailand, Papua New Guinea, Mexico, Ivory Coast, Sierra Leone, India, and the United States. It is particularly abundant in Japanese, Mexican, and American masks.
  - Subseries II.1: Africa
    - M18 Accession
      - African mask, M18.01 (Box 62)
      - Chokwe mask of Mwana Po (beautiful girl), M18.03 (Box 118)
    - M22 Accession
      - African mask, M22.01 (Box 124)
    - M23 Accession
      - African mask, M23.01 (Box 125)
  - Subseries II.2: Congo
    - M10 Accession
      - Mashamboy ceremonial mask (mwash a mbooy), M10.01 (Box 66)
  - Subseries II.3: Gabon
    - M21 Accession
      - Kota ceremonial mask from Ogowe River, M21.01 (Box 120)
    - M90 Accession
      - Modern cast of Bakota funerary mask, M90.034 (Box 63)
      - Modern cast of Mponge or Balumbo ceremonial mask, M90.051 (Box 183)
      - Modern cast of Mponge or Balumbo ceremonial mask, M90.50 (Box 181)
  - Subseries II.3: Guatemala
    - M20 Accession
      - Carnival mask, 1800-1899; M20.02 (Box 122)
  - Subseries II.4: Indonesia
    - M3 Accession
      - Javanese dance mask (male), M3.01 (Box 103)
      - Javanese dance mask (male), M3.02 (Box 100)
      - Javanese dance mask (male), M3.03 (Box 101)
      - Javanese dance mask (male), M3.04 (Box 104)
      - Javanese dance mask (male), M3.05 (Box 102)
    - M26 Accession
      - Javanese dance mask (male), 1750-1799; M26.01 (Box 165)
  - Subseries II.5: Italy
    - M2 Accession
      - Female mask (possibly a saint), circa 1800; M2.01 (Box 98)
      - Male mask (possibly a saint), circa 1800; M2.02 (Box 99)
  - Subseries II.6: Ivory Coast
    - M18 Accession
      - Dan mask of forest demon, M18.02 (Box 117)
    - M21 Accession
      - Ceremonial mask, M21.02 (Box 123)
    - M90 Accession
      - Modern cast of Guro ceremonial mask, M90.02 (Box 169)
      - Modern cast of Guro ceremonial mask (Ram), M90.016 (Box 167)
      - Modern cast of Guro ceremonial mask, M90.017 (Box 170)
      - Modern cast of Baule ceremonial mask (Hyena), M90.018 (Box 166)
      - Modern cast of Guro ceremonial mask, M90.028 (Box 175)
      - Modern cast of Dan ceremonial mask of Poro Secret Society, M90.030 (Box 176)
      - Modern cast of Baule ceremonial mask (possibly a god), M90.038 (Box 177)
      - Modern cast of Guro ceremonial mask, M90.039 (Box 179)
      - Modern cast of Baule ceremonial mask (Kakagye or Kuamnanbo), M90.04 (Box 179)
      - Modern cast of Baule ceremonial Mask (possibly Nyamye), M90.050 (Box 180)
  - Subseries II.7
    - M1 Accession
      - Noh mask, M1.01 (Box 67)
      - Noh mask of adult male (possibly a warrior), M1.02 (Box 68)
      - Noh mask of adult male (possibly a warrior), M1.03 (Box 69)
      - Noh mask of adult male (possibly a warrior or demon), M1.04 (Box 70)
      - Noh mask of adult male (possibly a warrior or bandit), M1.05 (Box 71)
      - Noh mask of young male, M1.06 (Box 72)
      - Noh mask of a demon, M1.07 (Box 73)
      - Noh mask of a demon, M1.08 (Box 74)
      - Noh mask of mad male (possibly Kantan Otoko), M1.10 (Box 75)
      - Noh mask, M1.11 (Box 76)
      - Noh mask of old male (Maijo), M1.12 (Box 77)
      - Noh mask of old male (possibly Kojijo), M1.13 (Box 78)
      - Noh mask of old male (Okina), M1.14 (Box 79)
      - Noh mask of old male (possibly Okina), M1.15 (Box 80)
      - Noh mask of old male (Kojijo type), M1.16 (Box 81)
      - Noh mask of adult male (Otobide), M1.17 (Box 82)
      - Noh mask of a demon (Kumasaka), M1.20 (Box 83)
      - Noh mask of a demon, M1.22 (Box 84)
      - Noh mask of a demon (possibly Shishiguchi), M1.24 (Box 85)
      - Noh mask of god, M1.25 (Box 86)
      - Kyogen mask of adult female (Oto), M1.26 (Box 65)
      - Kyogen mask of adult female (Oto), M1.27 (Box 87)
      - Kyogen mask of adult female (possibly Oto), M1.28 (Box 88)
      - Kyogen mask of adult male, M1.29 (Box 65)
      - Kyogen mask of old male (possibly Noborihige), M1.30 (Box 89)
      - Kyogen mask of adult male (possibly Enmei-Kwaia), M1.31 (Box 90)
      - Kyogen mask of young female, M1.32 (Box 91)
      - Kyogen mask of a demon (Buaku), M1.34 (Box 92)
      - Bugaku mask of a demon, M1.36 (Box 93)
      - God or Demon mask, M1.37 (Box 94)
      - Young female mask, M1.38 (Box 95)
      - Demon mask, M1.39 (Box 96)
      - Demon mask, M1.40 (Box 97)
    - M7 Accession
      - Noh mask of adult male (Hakuryo, the fisherman in "Hagoromo"), M7.01 (Box 105)
    - M11 Accession
      - Gigaku mask of sacred bird (Karura), M11.01 (Box 112)
  - Subseries II.9: Liberia
    - M90 Accession
      - Modern cast of ceremonial mask of Poro Secret Society, M90.040 (Box 178)
  - Subseries II.10: Mexico
    - M12 Accession
      - Carnival mask, modern; M12.01 (Box 114)
      - Carnival mask, modern; M12.02 (Box 113)
      - Carnival mask, modern; M12.02 (Box 113)
    - M13 Accession
      - Carnival mask (miniature or for a child), modern; M13.01 (Box 119)
    - M14 Accession
      - Carnival mask, modern; M14.01 (Box 64)
      - Carnival mask, modern; M14.02 (Box 64)
    - M20 Accession
      - Carnival mask, M20.01 (Box 121)
    - M24 Accession
      - Carnival mask mold, 1800-1899; M24.01 (Box 126)
      - Carnival mask mold, 1800-1899; M24.02 (Box 127)
      - Carnival mask mold, 1800-1899; M24.03 (Box 128)
      - Carnival mask mold, 1800-1899; M24.04 (Box 129)
      - Carnival mask mold, 1800-1899; M24.05 (Box 130)
      - Carnival mask mold, 1800-1899; M24.06 (Box 131)
      - Carnival mask mold, 1800-1899; M24.07 (Box 132)
      - Carnival mask mold, 1800-1899; M24.08 (Box 133)
      - Carnival mask mold, 1800-1899; M24.09 (Box 134)
      - Carnival mask mold, 1800-1899; M24.10 (Box 135)
      - Carnival mask mold, 1800-1899; M24.11 (Box 136)
      - Carnival mask mold, 1800-1899; M24.12 (Box 138)
      - Carnival mask mold, 1800-1899; M24.13 (Box 137)
      - Carnival mask mold, 1800-1899; M24.14 (Box 139)
      - Carnival mask mold, 1800-1899; M24.15 (Box 140)
      - Carnival mask mold, 1800-1899; M24.16 (Box 141)
      - Carnival mask mold, 1800-1899; M24.17 (Box 142)
      - Carnival mask mold, 1800-1899; M24.18 (Box 143)
      - Carnival mask mold, 1800-1899; M24.19 (Box 144)
      - Carnival mask mold, 1800-1899; M24.20 (Box 146)
      - Carnival mask mold, 1800-1899; M24.21 (Box 145)
      - Carnival mask mold, 1800-1899; M24.22 (Box 147)
      - Carnival mask mold, 1800-1899; M24.23 (Box 148)
      - Carnival mask mold, 1800-1899; M24.24 (Box 149)
      - Carnival mask mold, 1800-1899; M24.25 (Box 150)
      - Carnival mask mold, 1800-1899; M24.26 (Box 151)
      - Carnival mask mold, 1800-1899; M24.27 (Box 152)
      - Carnival mask mold, 1800-1899; M24.28 (Box 154)
      - Carnival mask mold, 1800-1899; M24.29 (Box 153)
      - Carnival mask mold, 1800-1899; M24.30 (Box 155)
      - Carnival mask mold, 1800-1899; M24.31 (Box 156)
      - Carnival mask mold, 1800-1899; M24.32 (Box 157)
      - Carnival mask mold, 1800-1899; M24.33 (Box 158)
      - Carnival mask mold, 1800-1899; M24.34 (Box 160)
      - Carnival mask mold, 1800-1899; M24.35 (Box 159)
      - Carnival mask mold, 1800-1899; M24.36 (Box 161)
      - Carnival mask mold, 1800-1899; M24.37 (Box 162)
      - Carnival mask mold, 1800-1899; M24.38 (Box 163)
      - Carnival mask mold, 1800-1899; M24.39 (Box 164)
    - M90 Accession
      - Modern cast of ceremonial mask from Teotihuacan, ca. 700 CE, M90.0208 (Box 173)
      - Modern cast of ceremonial mask from Teotihuacan, ca. 700 CE, M90.0209 (Box 173)
  - Subseries II.11: New Guinea (Sepik River)
    - M90 Accession
      - Modern cast of Ceremonial mask, M90.0112 (Box 168)
  - Subseries II.12: Nigeria
    - M90 Accession
      - Modern cast of Benin pendant mask, M90.058 (Box 182)
  - Subseries II.13: North America
    - M15 Accession
      - Northwest American Indian ceremonial mask, M15.01 (Box 115)
    - M16 Accession
      - Northwest American Indian ceremonial mask, M16.01 (Box 116)
    - M90 Accession
      - Modern cast of Inuit ceremonial mask, M90.0206 (Box 171)
      - Modern cast of dance mask from the Northwest, M90.0214 (Box 174)
      - Modern cast of Inuit ceremonial mask, M90.0224 (Box 174)
  - Subseries II.14: Sri Lanka
    - M4 Accession
      - Shaman's mask, M4.01 (Box 184)
  - Subseries II.15: Thailand
    - M5 Accession
      - Theatrical mask, M5.01 (Box 107)
      - Theatrical mask, M5.02 (Box 108)
      - Theatrical mask, M5.03 (Box 109)
      - Theatrical mask, M5.04 (Box 110)
      - Theatrical mask, M5.05 (Box 111)
  - Subseries II.16: United Stated
    - M90 Accession
      - Modern cast of North American Indian ceremonial dance mask from Florida, M90.0206A (Box 172)
  - Subseries II.17: Zaire
    - M8 Accession
      - Ceremonial mask, helmet mask, M8.01 (Box 106)
- Series III: Stage Models
  This collection contains 30 models, both models of historic theatres and set designs for specific productions. The models were acquired between 1911 and the 1960s. The set designs were largely the gifts of the various people involved with productions, from set designers to producers, and were acquired fairly consistently throughout the museum’s existence. The theatre models, on the other hand, were either gifts of Brander Matthews and other Dramatic Museum patrons or directly commissioned by the Museum, and were planned to display the full history of the theater when taken together. Global breadth appears to have been the goal of the BMDM’s curators, who were desirous of adding a Spanish theatre model to the collection.
  A broad rather than deep collection, it nevertheless has concentrations of French, English, American, and Japanese models. The earliest model, depicting a production of Leah Kleschna at the Manhattan Theatre in New York, was built in 1904. The latest models, both set designs, were built in 1966 for Japanese productions.
  The several Joseph Urban set models which the BMDM had collected to illustrate various parts of that influential man’s career were added to the over 300 set models in the Joseph Urban Papers when his widow presented them to the Museum in 1955, and are described in the Urban finding aid.
  The numbering is that used in Donald Pace’s Catalogue of the Brander Matthews Collection of Theatre Models (New York: Barnard College, 1973).
  - Subseries III.1: Historical Models
    - Model of the Roman Theatre in Orange, France built in the 2nd century CE, B01; Leo Devred
      Model shows large auditorium, stage, and elaborate scaenae frons as they probably appeared during the time of the theatre's use until its closing in the fourth century. Exterior and interior shown in great detail. Scale is 1:100.
    - Model of a platform stage for the Valenciennes Mystery Play; France, 1547, B02; Duvignaud and Gabin (Location RBML Mezzanine)
      Model is based on frontispiece of the manuscript of the Valenciennes Mystery Play, illustrated by Hubert Cailleau. God's throne and Hell's mouth frame the large stage, with a number of 'stations' in between. Created by Duvignaud and Gabin under the direction of Marius Sepet. Scale is 3:100.
    - Model of an English medieval pageant wagon of the 14th century, B03; Joseph Wickes
      Conjectural model of a pageant wagon, halted in town square for the Chester Play of Noah. Based on a 1911 production by Winthrop Ames at the New Theatre in New York. Created by Joseph Wickes under the direction of Hamilton Bell. Scale is 1:24.
    - Model of a platform stage in an English innyard of the 16th century, B04; Joseph Wickes
      King's Players performing The Nice Wanton (1550) on a scaffold stage in a Tudor innyard. Based on a 1911 production by Winthrop Ames at the New Theatre in New York. Created by Joseph Wickes under the direction of Hamilton Bell. Scale is 1:24.
    - Model of the Fortune Theatre; London, 1600, B06; James P. Maginnis (Location RBML- near Donor's Room)
      The Fortune playhouse opened one year after the Globe. Created by James P. Maginnis under the direction of Walter H. Godfrey. Scale is 3:100.
    - Model of a Renaissance theater setting of the early 16th century, based on Serlio, B07; Joseph Wickes
      Model represents a combination of Serlio's comic and tragic settings, illustrating the use of forced perspective popular with Renaissance designers. Created by Joseph Wickes under the direction of Hamilton Bell.
    - Model of the setting for La Folie de Clidamant by Alexandre Hardy as seen at the Hotel de Bourgogne, Paris, ca. 1630, B08; Davignaud and Gabin
      Shows the use of simultaneous settings at the Hotel de Bourgogne. With B11, shows differing methods of staging in 17th century French theatre. Based on sketch in Le Memoire de Mahelot; created by Davignaud and Gabin under the direction of Emile Perrin.
    - Model of the 17th century Theatre du Palais-Royal, Paris, B09
      Small cross-sectional model of the interior of the first theatre in France with a permanent proscenium and a stage designed for wing and drop scenery. Theater opened 1641; Moliere's theatrical home 1660-73.
    - Model of the 17th century Theatre du Palais-Royal, Paris, B10
    - Model of the Salle des Machines, theater in the Tuilieries, Paris, in 1671, B11; Alfred Devred
      Represents a setting for Psyche by Moliere and Corneille, based upon a 1906 revival of the play at the Theatre Francaise. With B08, the model illustrates differing methods of staging in 17th century French theatre. La Salles de Machines was a large and extravagently-equipped theatre built by Gaspare Vigarani in a wing of the Tuileries.
    - Model of an outdoor theatre at Versailles, 1664, B12
      Represents Les Plaisirs de l'Isle Enchantee, a ballet with text and choreography by Moliere, commissioned by Louis XIV. The spectacle was performed in May 1664 on a stage built especially for the occasion. Model based on an engraving by Israel Sylvestre.
    - Model of the Duke of York's Playhouse, London, 1661, B13; Klaus Holm
      Model shows the deep apron, proscenium doors, and wing and drop scenery typical of theatres during the Restoration. A converted indoor tennis court, the Duke's Playhouse opened in January 1661. Created by Klaus Holm from research by Dr. Elizabeth Scanlan.
    - Model of the Drury Lane; London, 1778, B14; James P. Maginnis
      Depiction of the "screen scene" from A School for Scandal by Richard Brinsley Sheridan. Shows the use of wing and drop scenery on a deep stage, the depth of the forestage, proscenium doors, and stage boxes. Created by James P. Maginnis under the direction of Walter H. Godfrey, based on a contemporary print.
    - Set model for Legend of the White Snake; Chinese Mechanical Theatre, B37 (Location RBML Mezzanine)
      Large representation of a scene from the Chinese classical work
    - Toy Orchestra, B40
  - Subseries III.2: Set Models
    - Set model for Les Deux Trouvailles de Gallus, Comedie Francaise, 1923, B15; Leo Devred
      Model of the setting for Les Deux Trouvailles du Gallus, a combination of Victor Hugo's plays Margarita and Esca.
    - Set model for Leah Kleschna, Manhattan Theatre, New York, 1904, B16; Gates and Morange
      Set model of fifth act of Leah Kleschna, an orchard near Neustadt, Austria. The Manhattan Theatre (not to be confused with Hammerstein's Manhattan on 34th between Broadway and 6th Avenue) stood at 6th Ave and 33rd St.
    - Set model for Herod, Lyric Theatre, New York, 1909, B17; Ernest Albert
      Depiction of Herod at the Lyric Theatre on 42nd St between Broadway and 8th Ave. The setting reflects the opulence of early 19th century settings and a pioneering use of varying levels. Designed by Ernest Albert of the Lee-Lash Studios.